vcuhealth.org 2006-06-20

# Virginia Commonwealth University Health System, MCV Hospitals and Physicians: Services & Programs

The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices of official Virginia Commonwealth University Health System (VCUHS) web pages (defined as an Institutional Web Page in the [**VCU Web Publishing Guidelines**](http://www.vcu.edu/guidelines/)) and is in accordance with the following statement. 

> _It is the policy of the Commonwealth of Virginia that personal information about citizens will be collected only to the extent necessary to provide the service or benefit desired; that only appropriate information will be collected; that the citizen shall understand the reason the information is collected and be able to examine their personal record which is maintained by a public body._

The VCU Health System Website does not require that any personal information be supplied in order to download publicly available files or reports. 

In addition to the VCU Health System Web Privacy Statement, specific notices about the collection and use of any personal information associated pages requesting such information will be available.

**What is collected and how is it used**

When you visit the VCU Health System web site we collect the following non-personal information

  * Your IP address 
  * Date and Time 
  * Pages visited 
  * Type of browser used 
  * Referring web page, if present

None of this information is associated with you as an individual and is used strictly for statistical reporting purposes in order to assess demands and usage for planning purposes.

Some VCU Health System web sites require you to provide personal information in order to provide services requested by you.  If you choose to share personal information with us by sending us an Email message or by filling out an electronic form with personal information, we will use the information only for the purposes you authorized or in support of VCUHS supported programs.  Should you not desire to provide this personal information, we will be unable to provide you some of the services which we offer online.  Each VCU Health System web site that collects personal information will include a statement as to the purpose for collecting such personal information and how that information will be used.

**Cookies**

> _A cookie is is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a World Wide Web Server and stored on your desktop computer.   The cookie is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. The primary purpose of cookies is to identify users in order to prepare customized Web pages for them._

VCU Health System web sites do not use cookies.

**Security**

Virginia Commonwealth University hosts the VCU Health System web pages and provides the following security:

_To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online, consistent with VCU policies and the laws and regulations of the Commonwealth of Virginia._

**Information Disclosure**

Any personal information that one chooses to supply will be maintained exclusively within VCU Health System and will not be supplied to any other non-VCU Health System entity or organization except as provided by law.  Information you provide is only used to provide requested services and for internal statistics.

**Disclaimer**

This site contains links to external (non-VCU Health System) web sites.  VCU Health System is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such web sites.

**Contacting Us**

If you have additional questions or concerns about our privacy policies, please send Email to the VCU Health System Webmaster at [**vcuhs@hsc.vcu.edu**](mailto:vcuhs@hsc.vcu.edu). If you wish to review or change information gathered about you via an official VCU Health System web site, you may contact the VCU Health System Webmaster who will assist you in locating the person responsible for that site so that you may make your request for that review or change directly with them.

© 2004 Virginia Commonwealth University Health System. (804) 828-9000.  
1250 East Marshall Street, Richmond, VA 23298  
[JCAHO Public Notice](http://www.vcuhealth.org/mcvp/JCAHOpub.asp) | Web Privacy Statement |  Contact the VCU Health System
